A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller 3rd Associates, Joan Dunlop papers FA252
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Population, 1954-1979; 5
  - Population Council, 1954-1979; 5.3
    - Adminstrative files, 1954-1977; 5.3.1
      - By-laws and certificate of incorporation, 1954-1957, 1959, 1963, 1967, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 206)
      - Population Council memos and sources for presidential speech, Summer/Fall 1975 (Box 17, Folder 204)
      - Population Council board meeting, 1975 October (Box 17, Folder 202)
    - Funding, 1963-1979; 5.3.2
      - Budget and administration, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 201)
      - Program budget, 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 17, Folder 205)
      - Population Council - Rockefeller Brothers Fund capital grant, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 203)
      - Capital Fund, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 207)
      - Grants, 1963-1967, 1972, 1974-1978 (Box 18, Folder 208)
      - Fund-raising, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 209)
      - Mauze Trust funding, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 210)
      - Cordelia S. May Charitable Trust funding, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 211)
      - Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 212)
    - Nobel Peace Prize, 1970-1972; 5.3.3
      - Nobel Peace Prize nomination consideration, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 213)
      - The Nobel Peace Prize, 1970 August (Box 18, Folder 214)
    - Presidential search and reorganization, 1959-1978; 5.3.4
      - Population Council reorganization, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 215)
      - Miro, Carmen, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 216)
      - Berelson, Bernard, 1967, 1973-1974, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 217)
      - Zeidenstein, George, 1973-1975 (Box 18, Folder 218)
      - Staff/ Roberts, Elizabeth, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 219)
      - Presidential search, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 220)
      - Wilhelm, Harry, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 221)
      - Allison, Graham, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 222)
      - Billington, James, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 223)
      - Wolfe, Gregory Baker, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 224)
      - Cowan, Jeffrey, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 225)
      - Engel, Julian, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 226)
      - Morris, Roger, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 227)
      - Muscat, Bob, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 228)
      - Goram Ohlin [EMPTY], n.d. (Box 19, Folder 229)
      - Stern, Ernest, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 230)
      - Hansen, Roger, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 231)
      - Lake, Anthony, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 232)
      - Bresman, Jack, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 233)
      - Berg, Alan, 1973, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 234)
      - Islam, Nural, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 235)
      - Nachmahoff, Arnold, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 236)
      - Early efforts to reorganize lead-in to Hopper Report, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 237)
      - Zeidenstein, George, 1973, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 238)
      - Population Council candidates folder, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 239)
      - Wilhelm, Harry, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 240)
      - George Zeidenstein's acceptance, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 241)
      - Board resignations, 1976-1978 (Box 19, Folder 242)
      - Presidential search, 1975- Wilhelm, Harry (Box 20, Folder 243)
      - Nominating committee meeting - Population Council, 1977 May 3 (Box 20, Folder 244)
      - Bunting Search Committee - Summer 1974, 1959, 1972-1975 (Box 20, Folder 245)
      - Bunting Search resumes, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 246)
      - Goldstein, Sidney, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 247)
      - Wahren, Carl, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 248)
      - Ness, Gayl, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 249)
      - Wharton, Cliff, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 250)
      - Strong, Maurice, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 251)
      - Welch, Finis, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 252)
      - Miro, Carmen, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 253)
      - Hood, David, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 254)
      - Population Council board reactions to new search, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 255)
      - Candidates, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 256)
      - Population Council board recruiting, 1975-1978 (Box 21, Folder 257)
      - Background material for board decision on new president, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 258)
  - Population Education, Inc., 1969-1979; 5.4
    Subseries 4 Population Education, Inc., consists of administrative files including funding and board meeting documentation. Secondly, the Project on Human Sexual Development records including John Gagnon fellowship files, the Cleveland Survey which was an empirical study of sexual learning in the home environment and the way community resources affect the process in Cleveland, Ohio, and a television project. Thirdly, sex education and women and development are represented in this subseries as well. Lastly, this subseries contains files on the World Population Conference of 1974. These include the Population Manifesto, news clippings and correspondence concerning John D. Rockefeller 3rd’s statement at the World Population Conference in Bucharest. The documents range from 1954-1979.
    - Administrative files, 1971-1979; 5.4.1
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) financials, 1976, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 259)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) - Form 990, 1973-1975, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 260)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) - computations, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 261)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) - financials, 1971-1976 (Box 21, Folder 262)
      - Solis, Faustina, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 263)
      - Rosow, Jerry, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 264)
      - Feinbloom, Richard, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 265)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) - board composition, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 266)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board: participation and reimbursement, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 267)
      - Brown, Ron, 1975-1977 (Box 22, Folder 268)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board meeting, 1978 December 5 (Box 22, Folder 269)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) executive committee meeting, 1978 November 9 (Box 22, Folder 270)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board meeting minutes, 1973-1976 (Box 22, Folder 271)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board: list of members, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 272)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI), New Project, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 273)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board meeting, 1977 June 23 (Box 22, Folder 274)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board meeting, 1976 December (Box 22, Folder 275)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board meeting - 1976 June 24-25 (Box 22, Folder 276)
      - Morton, Jim, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 277)
      - Smitherman, Genena, undated (Box 22, Folder 278)
      - Dunlop, Joan, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 279)
      - Leiman, Joan, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 280)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) - board of directors meeting minutes, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 281)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI): by-laws, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 282)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board: function and structure, 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 283)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) - monthly statements, 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 284)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) general correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 285)
      - Lee, Philip R. resume, 1972, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 286)
      - Lee, Philip: written examples of his work, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 287)
      - Fisher, Ben, 1975, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 288)
      - Fisher, Ben, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 289)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board: subcommittees, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 290)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) - financial information, 1975-1978 (Box 36, Folder 447)
      - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) - task force: Harvard agreement, 1971, 1974-1976 (Box 36, Folder 448)
    - Project on Human Sexual Development, 1972-1979; 5.4.2
      - General files, 1972-1979; 5.4.2.1
        - Advistory council meeting - 3 November 1975 (Box 23, Folder 291)
        - Task force on sexual development advisory council meeting, 29 July 1974 (Box 23, Folder 292)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) advisory council meeting - 6-7 November 1974 (Box 23, Folder 293)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) advisory council meeting, 2 March 1975 (Box 23, Folder 294)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) advisory council meeting, 24-25 July 1975 (Box 23, Folder 295)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) advisory council meeting- 26-26 March 1976 (Box 23, Folder 295A)
        - Hersh, Stephen, 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 296)
        - Harleston, Marie, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 297)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) advisory committee task force board composition, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 298)
        - Burch, Dean -resigned, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 299)
        - Sloan, Edith, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 300)
        - Levine, James Alan, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 301)
        - Perelman, Lew, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 302)
        - Gagnon, John-resume, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 303)
        - Lauder, Sheila, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 304)
        - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 305)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development - project outline, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 306)
        - Project for Human Sexual Development (PHSD) - John D. Rockefeller 3rd correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 24, Folder 307)
        - Human sexuality, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 308)
        - Modern Talking Picture Service- "Population and the American Future", 1973-1974, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 309)
        - Citizens Committee on Population and the American Future financial report, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 310)
        - Modern Talking Picture Service - Population and the American Future, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 311)
        - Citizens Committee on Population and the American Future, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 312)
        - National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH), 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 313)
        - Clark Foundation, 1975, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 314)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) general correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 25, Folder 315)
        - Sources, 1974-1976 (Box 25, Folder 316)
        - Human sexuality, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 317)
        - John D. Rockefeller 3rd grants- Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD), 1975-1978 (Box 25, Folder 318)
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) executor's meeting - 23 October 1978 (Box 25, Folder 319)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) general files, 1975-1977 (Box 25, Folder 320)
        - Line, David - Letter of Agreement etc., 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 321)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) - "After Boston Meeting", 1977 (Box 26, Folder 322)
        - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1974, 1976-1978 (Box 26, Folder 323)
        - Television and the Sexual Development of Children Proposal to National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH), 1976 (Box 26, Folder 324)
        - Carnegie Corporation of New York funding, 1974-1977 (Box 26, Folder 325)
        - Employees- staff salaries, 1974-1975 (Box 26, Folder 326)
        - Staff/legal, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 327)
        - Staff: general, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 328)
        - Benefits, 1975, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 328A)
        - Staff/ Gillis, James D., 1976 (Box 26, Folder 329)
        - Staff/Holt, Steven, 1975-1977 (Box 26, Folder 330)
        - Coburn, John, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 331)
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) board: correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 332)
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) reorganization, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 333)
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI)/Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) reorganization, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 334)
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) - Atwood Retreat, 2-4 December 1977 (Box 26, Folder 335)
        - Lee, Phil - correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 26, Folder 336)
        - Lynn, Bob, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 337)
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI)/Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) board, 1975-1977 (Box 26, Folder 338)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) papers, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 339)
        - Newsweek article sex - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD), 1978 (Box 27, Folder 340)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) workshop/retreat, 2-4 December 1977 (Box 27, Folder 341)
        - Proposal to the Cleveland Foundation by Population Education, Inc. (PEI) Cleveland program- Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD), 1978 (Box 27, Folder 342)
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI)/Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) board of trustees business, 1975-1978 (Box 27, Folder 343)
        - Roberts, Elizabeth, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 344)
        - Roberts, Elizabeth, 1974-1976 (Box 27, Folder 345)
      - Administrative files, 1973-1979; 5.4.2.2
        - Publication rights and royalties, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 346)
        - Public relations, 1975-1978 (Box 28, Folder 347)
        - Family policy, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 348)
        - General policy issues, 1976, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 349)
        - Fundraising file, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 350)
        - Correspondence from Elizabeth Roberts to John D. Rockefeller 3rd about Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD), 1975 January 6 (Box 28, Folder 351)
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI)/Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) budget and fundraising, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 352)
        - Legal, 1974-1975, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 353)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) -special studies program, undated (Box 28, Folder 354)
        - Staff salaries and benefits, 1974, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 355)
        - Bank accounts, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 356)
        - Financial/administration, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 357)
        - Budgets, 1975-1977 (Box 28, Folder 358)
        - Consultants, 1974-1975 (Box 28, Folder 359)
        - Rothschild, Dina, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 360)
        - Roberts, Elizabeth and Toomey, Michele resumes, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 360A)
        - Rintels, David, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 361)
        - Cooney, Joan, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 362)
        - Hood, David- resigned, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 362A)
        - Bertram S. Brown statement, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 363)
      - Fellowships, 1975-1979; 5.4.2.3
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI) Fellowships, 1977-1979 (Box 29, Folder 364)
        - Gagnon, John - Prohect on Human Sexual Development (PHSD), 1975-1978 (Box 28, Folder 365)
        - Population Education, Inc. (PEI)/Project on Human Sexual Developmenr (PHSD) fellowships, 1975, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 366)
        - Gagnon, John, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 367)
        - Gagnon, John, 1975-1977 (Box 29, Folder 368)
        - Gagnon, John, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 369)
      - Cleveland Survey, 1975-1979; 5.4.2.4
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD)- Cleveland, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 370)
        - Cleveland Advisory Council, 1975, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 371)
        - Cleveland Foundation, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 372)
        - Cleveland Foundation - trustee meeting, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 373)
        - Institute for Survey Research, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 374)
        - Cleveland Program, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 375)
        - Siegel, Alberta, 1976-1977 (Box 29, Folder 376)
        - Staff/Cleveland/Aptekar-Litton, Lucille, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 377)
        - Aptekar-Litton, Lucille, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 378)
        - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 30, Folder 379)
        - Bush Foundation - Cleveland funding, 1977 January 21 (Box 30, Folder 380)
        - Brush Foundation - Cleveland funding, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 381)
        - George Gund Foundation - Cleveland funding, 1976-1978 (Box 30, Folder 382)
        - Cleveland budgets, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 383)
        - Cleveland resource analysis, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 384)
        - Cleveland program proposal, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 385)
        - Cleveland program funding, 1975-1979 (Box 30, Folder 386)
        - Cleveland program analysis, 1976-1977 (Box 30, Folder 387)
        - Cleveland survey documents (Box 30, Folder 388)
        - A Study of Community Resources for Sexual Learning in Greater Cleveland - draft copy, undated (Box 30, Folder 389)
        - Parent Attitude and Practices Study - interm document, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 390)
      - Television project, 1975-1978; 5.4.2.5
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) - TV projects, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 391)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD) - TV and Sexuality workshop report, 7-8 April 1978 (Box 31, Folder 392)
        - TV Film, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 393)
        - Articles on TV, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 394)
        - Children's television: the issues of sex and violence, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 395)
        - Writer's workshop, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 396)
        - Analysis of TV programs for John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 397)
        - Carter, Virginia, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 398)
        - The John and Mary R. Markle Foundation grant, 1975-1977 (Box 31, Folder 399)
        - Television activities funding, 1975-1977 (Box 31, Folder 400)
        - Ford Foundation: television project, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 401)
        - The Arca Foundation: television project, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 402)
        - Television activites correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 31, Folder 403)
        - Project on Human Sexual Development (PHSD): Ojai TV speech - Markle Foundation proposal, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 404)
        - Ojai: "Television and Sexuality", 1978 (Box 31, Folder 405)
        - Ojai: Dunlop "Thank You" correspondence, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 406)
        - Ojai: summary of proceedings, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 407)
        - Ojai materials - workshop on Television and Sexuality, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 408)
        - Workshop on Television and Sexuality, Ojai, California: John D. Rockefeller 3rd speech, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 409)
        - Special invitations via John D. Rockefeller 3rd to Workshop pn Television and Sexuality, Ojai, California, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 410)
        - Liebert, Robert speech - Workshop on Television and Sexuality, Ojai, California, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 411)
        - John Gagnon speech - Workshop on Television and Sexuality, Ojai, California, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 412)
        - Greer, Germaine - Ojai correspondence, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 413)
        - Workshop on Television and Sexuality participants, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 414)
        - Workshop on Television and Sexuality participant comments and suggested follow-up, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 415)
    - Sex education, 1969-1978; 5.4.3
      - Youth Values Project training program materials, 1977 February 5 (Box 32, Folder 416)
      - Youth Values project, 1975-1978 (Box 32, Folder 417)
      - Contemporary influences on sexual response, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 418)
      - Sex education/Human sexuality financial contributions, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 419)
      - Research on human sexuality, 1973, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 420)
      - Community Sex Information (CSI), 1971-1973 (Box 32, Folder 421)
      - Sex education, 1969, 1971-1973 (Box 33, Folder 422)
      - Youth Values Project - Washington meeting, 5 September 1978 (Box 33, Folder 423)
      - Sex education - Youth Policy studies, undated (Box 33, Folder 424)
      - New Initatives in Sex Education - meeting 12 June 1978 (Box 33, Folder 425)
      - New Initatives in Sex Education Task Force, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 426)
      - Meeting on sex education, Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF) conference room, 12 June 1978 (Box 33, Folder 427)
      - Sex education - Sex Information and Education Council of the U.S. (SIECUS), 1970, 1973, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 428)
    - Women and development, 1974-1979; 5.4.4
      - Women and development, 1974-1975 (Box 34, Folder 429)
      - Women's Forum Inc., 1978-1979 (Box 34, Folder 430)
      - United Nations and women, 1974-1975 (Box 34, Folder 431)
      - Plight of Third World Women, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 432)
      - International Women's Year: reports and media coverage, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 433)
      - Women and development, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 434)
      - Zeidenstein, Sondra, 1974-1976 (Box 34, Folder 440)
      - Women and development - report and commentary on IRDP women's programme: the first year, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 449)
    - World Population Conference, 1974, 1973-1976; 5.4.5
      - World Population Conference, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 435)
      - World Population Conference correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 34, Folder 436)
      - World Population Conference articles, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 437)
      - Post World Population Conference correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 34, Folder 438)
      - Pre World Population Conference issues work-up center of concern, 1-4 April 1974 (Box 34, Folder 439)
      - Population Manifesto, 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 441)
      - World Population Conference - Population Manifesto, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 442)
      - World Population Conference, 1973-1975 (Box 37, Folder 450)
      - World Population Conference - clippings, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 451)
      - Population - clippings, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 452)